in five minutes or less alpine js is a
minimalist lightweight javascript
framework it is like jquery for modern
web development thanks to alpine.js we
don't have to make a fully fledged
react.js application if we want to make
our website interactive with alpine.js
we can build the interactive components
that most websites need like models
accordions carousels tabs or
notifications among others by writing
almost no code at all as we will see
right now all we have to do is add
attributes to our html elements and
alpine yes we'll do the rest let's build
a simple counter with alpine.js to see
how easy it is to use first we import
the alpine jgs script in our html then
we are going to create a div and give it
the attribute x theta which will have a
count property starting at 0. now any
element inside of that div will be able
to read and modify the count property
let's now add a button to increase the
count and for this we will use the alpha
and js attribute x on with the click
event and finally let's display the
count value to the user using the x text
attribute on a span element now we test
and as you can see it works pretty
pretty well that was incredibly easy as
you can see all we have to do is add the
x-attributes to our html elements in
alpha js we'll read them and do the rest
it will even refresh the ui and keep
track of the data for us let's now build
a drop down component in a new div let's
use x data again to initialize a open
property to false inside of that div we
will make a button to change open to the
opposite of what open currently is that
means that if open is currently false it
will change it to true and if open is
currently true we will change it to
false in another div using the x show
attribute we will tell alpine.js to only
show it when open is true we will also
add the x transition to the div to get a
sweet css transition when the content
shows and hides and as you can see it
works pretty well including css hiding
and showing transitions how easy was
that we just built a counter and a hide
and show component with css transitions
writing no javascript at all if you are
worried that it might be hard to
remember or find all the x dash
attributes that alpha js has don't worry
there are only 15 of them alpine jjs is
pretty small but you can combine all of
them to build really cool stuff i think
alpine.js will be especially useful for
people like web publishers that don't
want to learn or build a full react.js
application but still want to add
interactivity to their websites let me
know in the comments if you like alpine
js and what are your opinions on it and
also if you like it a lot let me know if
you would like me to make a full
tutorial on alpine.js and we will make
it happen and don't forget if you want
to learn to code and you want to do it
for free then please click the link
below and i will see you there thank you
for watching today stay happy stay free
it's kimchi salaam hamidah come join me
see you on the next one bye